A Guide to the Rockefeller University records, Student records, Nicholas A. Acheson FA235
Rockefeller Archive Center
Rockefeller University records, Student records, Nicholas A. Acheson
1965-1969
Rockefeller Archive Center
Rockefeller Institute for Medical Research
Acheson, N. H.
Rockefeller University
FA235
3.08 Cubic Feet 7 boxes. Extent volume is approximate.
6 boxes and 1 black box.
Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements
Materials requiring specialized equipment for access (film, audio, video, slides) may be closed to research dependent on availability of the applicable equipment
Brittle or damaged items, or materials otherwise in need of preservation care, may be closed to researchers at the discretion of the RAC Head of Archival Services/Head of Reference.
Scope and Contents
Photocopied from researcher's original memo Data Notebooks 1. 10/1/65-1/1/67. 2. 1/1/67-6/1/67. 3. 6/1/67-1/1/68. 4. 1/1/68-3-8-68. 5. 3/12/68-7/9/69. 6. 7/9/68-10/21/68. 7. 11/5/68-2/5/69. 8. 3/11/69-6/17/69. 9. 6/27/69- Electron microcopy records: 1. /65-4/16/68. 2. 4/16/68-
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Gift from Nicolas H. Acheon, Aug 18, 1975. Received March, 1976.
Conditions Governing Access
Collection is open for scholarly research.
File Plan note
Former Classification: I 460 Ac45
Conditions Governing Access note
This collection is open for research.
Arrangement
Arranged by subject and in chronological order.
Arboviruses; Animal behavior; Life sciences; Medicine, Preventive; Biochemistry; Chemistry; Cell and biomolecular sciences; Biology -- Research; Medical technology; Medical sciences; Medical research; Medical education; Science -- Study and teaching; Rockefeller Institute for Medical Research; Acheson, N. H.; Rockefeller University
- Nicholas H. Acheson, 1965-1969
  Biographical/Historical note
  Biographical note
  1942 Born March 11, Boston, Massachusetts
  1963 A.B. Harvard College, Cambridge, Massachusetts
  September 1963-June 1969 Student at Rockefeller University
  1969 Ph. D. Rockefeller University, New York, New York. Dissertation title: "The structure and replication of Semliki Forest Virus, a mosquito-borne animal virus" Dr. Igor Tamm research advisor.
  - Laboratory notes, 1965-1969
    Scope and Contents note
    9 data notebooks on the Semliki Forest Virus. Notebooks labeled SFV and dated. Includes experiments, graphs, charts. In approximate chronological order. Notebook covers removed and pages numbered.
    Arrangement
    Chronological order.
    - 10/1/1965-1/1/1967 (Box 1)
    - 1/1/1967-6/1/1967, 2 folders: pp 1-109, pp 110-215 (Box 1)
    - 6/1/1967-1/1/1968, 2 folders: pp 1-139, pp 140-276 (Box 1)
    - 1/1/1968-3/8/1968, 2 folders: pp 1-132, pp 133-242 (Box 1)
    - 3/12/1968-7/4/1968, 2 folders: pp 1-123, pp 124-238 (Box 2)
    - 7/9/1968-10/21/1968, 2 folders: pp 1-128, pp 129-245 (Box 2)
    - 11/5/1968-2/5/1969, 2 folders: pp 1-143, pp 144-243 (Box 2)
    - 3/1/1969-6/17/1969, 2 folders: pp 1-105, pp 106-190 (Box 3)
    - 6/27/1969-8/12/1969 (Box 3)
  - Electron micrographs, 1965-1969
    In chronological order.
    Slides stored in yellow boxes and numbered 1 to 13 by researcher. Electron micrograph records 1965-1969; in 2 notebooks. Notebook covers removed and pages numbered.
    - Cytology course and SFV (Semliki Forest Virus) project, Black box (Box 4)
    - Slide box number 1, Black box (Box 4)
      Glass slides in long envelopes labeled RCA plates; others: 14 labeled SFV; 1 labeled. Nuc; 12 labeled HEL.
    - Slide box number 2, 12/9/1965-1/6/1966; Glass slides (Box 5)
    - Slide box number 3, 1/22/1966-1/23/1966; Glass slides (Box 5)
    - Slide box number 4, 1/29/1966; Glass slides (Box 5)
    - Slide box number 5, 1/29/1966-2/11/1966; Glass slides (Box 5)
    - Slide box number 6, 2/11/1966-3/26/1966; Glass slides (Box 6)
    - Slide box number 7, 4/7/1966-7/20/1966; Glass slides (Box 6)
    - Slide box number 8, 7/20/1966-7/21/1966; Glass slides (Box 6)
    - Slide box number 9, 7/28/1966-11/19/1966; Glass slides (Box 6)
    - Slide box number 10, 11/15/1966-11/20/1967; Glass slides (Box 7)
    - Slide box number 11, 11/17/1966-2/14/1969; Glass slides (Box 7)
    - Slide box number 12, 2/16/1969-5/5/1969; Glass slides (Box 7)
    - Slide box number 13, 5/5/1969-5/8/1969; Glass slides (Box 7)
    - Electron microscopy records, 2 folders. Notebook covers removed and pages numbered. (Box 7)
      - 5/20/1965-4/16/1968
      - 4/16/1968-5/6/1969